come on for less time I want a little
bit early just because I wanted to give
my answer to the five questions and also
talk about conflict and the shopping
cart post that I came across on Facebook
and this little piece of conflict that
is in my life at the moment and figuring
it out and what that brings up in me but
what I got right before going live
concerns part of me that doesn't want to
go big party because one do things wrong
and so part of my freeze response in my
euro system is like if I'm going to get
if I could get it wrong I'm not going to
do it at all and so it just shuts it all
down so you just don't go live you might
say the wrong thing because that's where
a part of this complex the wrong word
but conflict came up was a couple videos
that I did last week where I talked
about art and my understanding at that
time and and person was watching as an
artist and and felt I was discrediting
art and artists in general and so I'm
sitting with what that means and we're
gonna have a conversation the two of us
soon but my learning in this is also
it's the person I care about and don't
want to hurt them even more than I don't
want to hurt general random people in
the world I really don't want to hurt
people that I care about who I know are
here to do good things but I also know
me and my personality I can't silence
myself my only other option is to freeze
because anything anyone says people
reacting to what they think you're
saying and that's everyone I have
another layer just with my cognitive
problems and a DD and autism and
everything else that like I start
telling the story no and I need these
four other pieces but my brain won't let
me ever get to those four other pieces
you only get this piece which is like
right you don't get all the other layers
and also just rewatching the videos I
was like yeah I can see how especially
when I was talking about my experience
University as a scientist how that looks
like I'm a discrediting artists but it
was more the culture of artists and also
if I'm gonna have this conversation with
this person at some point in time later
Jew Abbas will not be on my youtube
channel but having there's there's a lot
coming up because it's like the
difference between me working through my
inner right which very might might
be critical of artists like that's part
of being a scientist and going through
society is like learning what that isn't
but it's my own internal artist that I'm
struggling with right not the artist in
other people not the and so like this
comes up all the time in the in the
queer community and I don't quite
understand it like if somebody is
homophobic and then becomes gay right
comes out as gay and it's like oh now we
understand yeah you were a homophobic
asshole before but now it's
understandable and you're forgiven
whereas there's isn't any forgiveness
for all the homophobic assholes that
might come up later and like why they're
all just reacting to their own
suppressed sexuality whether that's you
know I don't know because my lawns turn
them on on women or mother because they
actually are attracted to men or what
like whatever that happens to be why is
it forgiven after the fact and so
there's that same piece of I don't know
there's just something there like that
it's how much of what we react to each
other is reacting to our own internal
struggle I would say nearly all of it
like there's what I said which I meant
to be about my own journey and art in
general but it wasn't didn't quite come
out properly as most of what I say
doesn't how I intended or how I want it
to come out right and then there's the
Peace of having like an individual
versus a group like I know there ended
groups that I am rather anti in my life
artists are not in them that doctors in
general the medical community because of
my history I am very critical of at the
same time doctor a doctor I don't think
any of them are bad I don't think about
like the vast majority might evil it's
it's the combination of them I feel the
same way but due to my history with
Christians and my childhood Christian
and Christianity in general has a womb
but a Christian doesn't like it it's the
individual versus the group and they're
very different I can critique the group
as a whole without necessarily
reflecting on the individual when I say
the Medical Systems in it for profit I
don't think every doctor is there just
to get money when I say you know
Christianity is hypocritical but anyway
sitting with how much is it my
responsibility to say something and
anticipate how it could land and being
someone who has put way too much energy
into that in the past and therefore does
basically zero of that now why don't I
note is there I still put a lot of
energy into that but it's not as it was
before and so again my response be
freeze I want to do nothing because I
might do something wrong
especially when it's only words like if
I'm you know untangling slumbered put
untangling a bomb and I could get it
wrong then yeah don't do anything you
could do something wrong you can blow
everything up but when it's words like I
know there are truths that I don't talk
about online because I don't want them
to come off I know how they could come
off right my viewpoints on certain
things are controversial but I don't
want to offend people and that's the
general people and yet I also know you
can't change this world with us any
people and it's picking it's speaking my
truth and having faith that whatever is
supposed to happen will happen
because there is the first reaction was
definitely gee I wish I hadn't said that
I wish I could go back and what and I
was like oh wait there's nothing I said
that I think was wrong that I don't
stand behind it's the layers of context
underneath that aren't given in the
conversation there's nothing that I said
that I was like I wish I hadn't said
that if there are times but not in the
clips that I had seen I was like but I
could see how it could be seen as it was
see it's like oh yeah yeah now again I
guess when they first mentioned it I was
like what I never said anything critical
about art what I mean I don't remember
saying that
because it wasn't in my because in the
moment I didn't feel that's critical art
like I do when I'm being critical about
the medical system I absolutely know me
hoebuck medical system it didn't feel
that way
remember talking about it despite the
fact I talked about Arden gratuity for
the entire morning session of the one
with Elizabeth Gilbert anyway so then
one of my friends on Facebook posted
this this and I think it's very in
alignment and it also I put anyway the
shopping cart is the ultimate list
litmus test for whether a person is
capable of self governing to return the
shopping cart is an easy convenient task
and one which we all recognize as the
correct appropriate thing to do to
return the shopping cart is objectively
right there is no situation other than
dire emergencies in which a person is
not able to return their cart
simultaneously is not illegal to abandon
your shopping cart therefore the
shopping cart presents itself as an apex
example of whether a person will do what
is right without being forced to no one
will be no one will punish you for not
returning a shopping cart no one will
find you or kill you for not returning a
shopping cart you gain nothing by
returning the shopping cart you must
return the shopping cart out of the
goodness of your own heart you must
return the shopping cart because it is
the right thing to do because it is
correct a person who is unable to do
this is no better than an animal and
absolute savage who can only be made to
do what is right by threatening them
with a law and the force that stands
behind it the shopping cart is what
determines whether a person is good or
bad member of society and my friend
hand-written whether you do agree with
this or not and my answer was for the
test to work the assumption that
returning the car equals right must
first be established there are many
reasons not returning there are many
reasons not to return a cart if you
assume you know what is right and that
anyone not doing it must have a wrong
reason for doing this wrong thing that
you are doing something that is less
than right self-government means
returning the cart if you feel called to
and assuming others have valid to them
reasons for not doing so also most parts
have a deposit which skews the whole
thing anyways I wasn't aware American
carts don't actually have deposits
almost all Canadian ones do so her post
has a few comments on it but there's the
original post it has like 1.5 thousand
comments and
clicking on it it's really interesting
because it's a shopping cart right and
part of this analogy works where it's
like it's it's a fairly benign test and
yet the passion that people have above
it of yeah this is the right thing to do
you guys are all crappy human beings how
can we end up like that's the problem
that you think not returning a shopping
cart equals your crappy human being when
you have no idea what their life
circumstances are like one person in the
comments that stated that they have a
disability sometimes it's too hard for
them to walk it back and so they leave
it there and that ableism then people
were like well if you're able to walk
around the store if you're clearly
capable of putting it back you don't
live in their body you don't know what
it's like to not have to spend all of
your spoons for days to a grocery
shopping spending extra ones to do
something that's not illegal and isn't
right or wrong it's just this tiny like
even if 90% of people think it's the
right thing to do to return return the
shopping cart that doesn't actually mean
that it's the right thing to do there
are people who are like wait it's
people's job to go and collect the
shopping carts I'm taking someone's
drove away from them other people who
are like but yes but if you get out of
your car there's a shopping cart right
there then you can take that one and
that's perfect
I'm doing a good thing for the next
person but this idea that one it's just
right to return a shopping cart there is
no reason to not unless there's an
absolute emergency right then well
firstly if there is an absolute
emergency you've already said that it's
not okay so even if you already need
someone's died in the hustle you have to
run to get to them and you don't have
time to return the shopping cart are we
going to assume that's what happened
every time I was sitting there no and it
causes anger in the next person they
assume it was they did the wrong thing
therefore they did it for wrong reasons
then there was somebody who so there was
the person who said yes I left it there
actually on goodness I thought it was
the better thing to do the person with a
disability though that was both like
well if you can walk around the store
you can return and people who are like
look you can't walk then you should
certainly shouldn't be allowed to drive
all of which are very ablest you don't
understand what it's like to live in a
body that doesn't work clearly because
you think that you shouldn't be able to
drive when you can't walk those are two
very different things I know when I'm
capable of driving and whatnot
also no because I know I'm not capable
of driving I am more responsible than
the vast majority of people on the road
because I leave Co hosing when we have
dinner at 7:00 7:30 because I know my
brain will crash and I don't want to be
on the road with a brain that stark
optimal you know any people drive home
after a long day of work after five days
of work after weeks of work exhausted
ton way more than drinking drive way
more than do any kind of drug and drive
but that's just society that's like over
here what we're supposed to do because I
know when I'm brain fog I'm not at my
optimal I'm more cognizant to not drive
during those days even though especially
the beginning part of that stage I would
be better to drive the most people on
the road that's like doing assuming that
you know what's right in self governing
to me self governing is what I said it's
you do the right thing whatever you
think the right thing is if you think
the right things are turning the cart
return the cart if you think the right
things leaving it there for the worker
so do I leaving it there for the next
driver do that but it's like it's the
fact that we have different meaning
behind it right that if I see a cart I'm
going to assume and this was a whole so
part of it so a lot of what comes up
with ableism is what you do when you
have a disability often makes you look
lazy and inconsiderate and those are two
things that do not have a positive
correlation in our society whereas the
research I've done on being someone
who's chronically ill the best there's a
there's a correlative huge correlation
between people who think about others
before themselves people who are highly
altruistic people who have high empathy
people who are way more likely to be
disabled there for a lifetime of being
the opposite of lazy of giving yourself
without getting anything back and of
being overly considerate of other people
constantly thinking what am I going to
say where's it gonna land how are they
gonna what are the 15 layers they're
gonna get out of what I say
so let me craft it and therefore no
sentence comes out properly is not great
so it's like knowing that there's always
gonna be conflict how do we then deal
with it and one of the things that I'm
saying I'm about to go through the five
questions but it was just this shopping
cart thing it was like well that's a
weird let this test considering and you
first
have to establish that it's the right
thing to do to return their shopping
cart and then I assume that you know the
circumstances of somebody's like what
would Trump that right thing to do even
if it is the right thing to do
what is a bigger reason not to I think
we can both agree that a dying relative
there's gonna die right now is more
important than returning the shopping
cart what about if that's all day every
day you have a you have a loved one at
home who's on their deathbed right and
you're constantly worried when you're
away from them what if you're what you
know is someone you love just out of
urine hearing anxiety around people who
have no reason to be dying that they
might be right like there's
circumstances you can't understand about
someone unless you passed and one of the
reasons I'm very grateful for this
conflict this thing with my videos
that's coming up right now right now
this conversation is that this wouldn't
have happened if it was broadcast just
broadcast right if I didn't know this
person if she didn't feel comfortable
enough to bring up that I had offended
her then I wouldn't have the opportunity
to make it right in any way right to
explain the sub context to explain what
I meant to if and this is the difference
between like if I watch something in
Jordan Peterson pisses me off and I do a
comments video that's not and him you
know maybe like it's not actually
anything to do with him he doesn't need
to watch it it's my and I'm dealing
with it um and it's broadcast right like
I know he's never I'm not gonna try to
contact him and be like you got this
wrong right because I don't we don't
have a relationship
Jordan Buford second odd and yet that
happens all the time online right like
you've said something and put me you're
horrible human being for having done
that
and I think we all have that happen all
the time and then but now I'm far enough
along that I know it's my even when
I'm in the about that person it's
still a and so there's what I said
that had all the context behind it that
I didn't give there's what she took from
it right which that's all her context
behind that it's impossible to give
wasn't point of that understanding
problem but that one broadcast versus
distributed having a conversation having
a community of people that it isn't one
person in a million viewers because I
can't have a conversation with a million
viewers right what's the option of a
million if I pissed off a million
viewers it's that they they
they what's the word say troll but
that's not right
they get angry in the comments right
like it's all there's also just this
post about Megan Merkel and someone
calling her like a cold mother that she
wasn't very mature noble and she's
pretty her needs first of her kid I'm
like it's a 30 second video no one
should say that to a mom if you want to
critique her acting or her princess role
go ahead but do not say that about a
mother like that's not in the realm of
celebrity that is never okay to say
someone and that's maybe because in my
own way my answer the five questions if
we're getting off my kids cool there we
go oh my kids awake so Who am I
I am imperfect and learning as I go and
I'm learning to surrender and have faith
that exactly what is unfolding is
supposed to unfold including when I feel
like I've done something wrong
right my natural reaction is like okay I
have to Eve undone that thing which is
impossible never do that thing again in
the future which is also impossible
instead of the faith of you know what I
said the right thing in the right moment
and she got the reaction she was
supposed to get when she watched it and
there's something that will come from
having this V not broadcast and having
her bring it to my attention having us
have a conversation and I have faith
that the right thing will emerge exactly
as it's supposed to be who are my people
and this is where oh very much my people
are the people with the strength to
bring up when there is something that is
bothering them it takes a lot of
vulnerability to say like that thing
that you said hurt me
even if it's not wrong for the person to
say it and not wrong for you to have the
response the like letting the air clear
is part of the power of not having us be
broadcast and having it be something
that can like we're so anti conflict in
society that we push it away so strongly
that we create more of it right there's
workplaces where it's like you
constantly go and there's constantly
stress and struggle and tension because
you don't like her co-workers or
coworkers don't like you but you both
are there for a paycheck and you can't
really deal with it so you just like
deal with this underlying intention
instead of dealing with it right instead
of having a blow-up value which is I
don't think what we will be doing but
like
gamer then it clears the air you're like
I'll fine I'm done I don't care I quit
anyway
you're like somehow then something comes
out of it fine I don't care if I burn
this bridge and then that's kind of when
the magic happens that we can have that
same thing happen continually where you
you it's we're you have to be willing to
burn the bridge right you have to be
willing to say this thing hurt me and if
it's a big enough of a breaking point
than like this relationships like it's
like you have to be willing that the
relationship could break up in order to
repair it okay so my people are very
much people bring up problems and people
who keep showing up and trying their
best and they're on their own journey of
self-discovery and understand that like
no one gets it perfect and these things
are are gonna come up so what is my
purpose what is my purpose my purpose is
conversation and finding balance and
learning to obey whatever it is that
runs the universe and I am in my own way
of a bacon kicking it's very learning
more and more what do I need I need to
wake up to all that I have now and that
showed up this week and me feeling
stressed about these four conversations
that I'm planning and yesterday during
our together tech board meeting and
during our group and didn't happen until
during the board meeting yesterday where
I'm trying to plan these four
conversations one of which is solution
raising it's already happening and then
process raising that I still don't quite
know how to explain but like I really
want people to work through how do we
create a process together with 10,000
people so that we can create with that
many people from the bottom up not one
I'm still looking at but the other two
one of which is it's talking about the
dance and the five questions and more of
like the spiritual self-development part
I want a group of people to meet
together
I'm laughing because if I don't
Hispanics and the other one was having a
group of people who is passionate about
technology and like the social good that
can be done with technology and what
needs to be in place to do that having
those conversations he's turning the
board mediate I was like oh this is that
isn't it I already have that in my life
why am i cuz I was like trying to add
these four conversations plus the two
together tech ones then if I still have
the idea cafe and then I do one-off
conversations I have that's seven to
eight conversation
I'm having a week when I'm already
having two of them and one of them
anyway the one that's not put online
part of it is having them on my channel
so you can see that this is like my
journey my inner my interpersonal
journey with people you know the
technology piece the conversation
feasible solution raising and then part
of it so I have that I have that I've
heard you have that I already have a
place to show up and talk about the
dance and our own intervene and
sometimes that's not the week to do that
and sometimes it is and that's kind of
allowing things to happen as they are
it's not planned over the Omega group
isn't designed to be the dance isn't
designed to be the five questions but it
comes up and it interweaves and it's
game B and it's it's perfect exactly as
it is maybe I do want a more focused one
the same with the technology
conversation like these things
constantly come up and I love these
conversations and love and more and more
people are showing up but we're having
more and more interesting conversations
that if I try to folk for set one and
what if something amazing does come out
of the technology conversations then can
I put you know maybe the other people
that were beyond together tech and so
there's like the if beating clump like
they kept beating competition with
together tech but it's not actually but
all anyway just what I need is to open
up to that I already have everything I
need and yes these conversations that
I'm really looking for and trying to
find are 2:02 the fourth I'm already
there and the other two of the two
important ones are like my thing anyway
or that I feel called to do that won't
be my thing when other people join but
it's my thing I'm looking to make it our
thing right so that is what I need and
he's just wake up to that and find just
those two conversations which is what
social reasons already there and I was
only gonna add one of them the next week
anyway so adding process raising good
good
all right well what am i ready and able
to let go of and I don't know if this is
actually a correct answer cuz don't of
them actually able I'm willing to let go
of this I just don't know if I'm able
quite yet and but I'm learning and it's
a process and that's needing to not hurt
or defend people that it is a reflection
on me as a human being when somebody
gets offended that there's something I
shouldn't have done instead of one how
can I make it right if there is a way
right when I have it when I have a
million viewers is not gonna be possible
right you don't come on make an apology
video for every unless you do something
actually atrocious and if you've been
around stranger that said that I
probably wouldn't even a responded but
she's not running strangers she's as
important and someone I do care more
deeply about not offending and at the
same time if I take that on then it then
it paralyzes me that it makes me freeze
and not want to say anything to anyone
and do anything and neither of those are
good solutions like so yeah I'm letting
go of needing to not hurt people but
like in this surrender allowing that
whatever I say will land as it's
supposed to which frees me up to say it
better anyway and however they hear it
is also how they're supposed to hear it
and we're all on our own personal
journey and I've learned long ago that
when I have conflict with something like
what I feel anger and gross Ness about
them and something they did nine times
out of ten at least it's on me and not
them right it's my learning it's like
well here's why that doesn't feel right
for me here's what I'm here to learn
from it and a lot of times because I
can't in any way control that person
I've no contact with that person that
person doesn't know who I am you know
like Trump doesn't care who I am so if
I'm here to learn something from him
it's on me to learn it because he's not
gonna learn something for me and that
but if I'm also trying not to hurt
people and I'm not showing up 100% as
myself I'm not gonna get to do the good
that I'm here to do either so yes I
might not do any harm but I'm not gonna
get to do the good and that's for
especially with just just words like
words don't hurt but of course like
words hurt they have a real big
impactful meaning at the same time they
are just words they and that is where
like I know for me people have said some
very hurtful things and I've had a
process that you deal with it and my
nervous system responds to it and I've
still learned by learning from it like
okay yeah this neighbor keeps cuff
showing up and yelling at me for things
I can't control and what am I here to
learn from and why does she keep showing
up in my life
what is she here to teach me that you
know my sibling relationship ends and
what I've needed to learn from that and
grow and every interaction I don't wanna
call this one a negative one at all this
person sentiment
positive and they will continue to have
a positive impact in my life but um that
we consider this a negative interaction
right in society and therefore it's like
don't let it happen again don't like
push it down let's ignore it just it's
like none of that actually helps us
build the relationship helps clear the
error so that she can show up she
chooses to with without that being
underneath and I can show up without
that beam under me and and it takes two
people to clear the eye right if one of
you wants to push it away one of you
wants to deal with it I don't know what
you do and I'm very grateful that one
this person brought it to my attention
and didn't just either go away and get
and get angry and go away and not say
anything or um which is a response right
that is the flight response freeze which
is my response to conflict if like
somewhat don't that's not true I do what
she does I do I think that's why we have
a lot of common in them like I'll put up
with a lot and then when it's like I
know this is my thing to say I know this
is like my there's something here that's
not right and I need to say it and even
if it's not right that it's not right
right even if it's like my my shadow and
my drama that's showing up in this
moment it's still something that's fine
to say and it's still something that has
to be said and then sometimes I know
that it's not it's like okay you know
that is your drama that is your thing
you keep that you work through that and
if somebody else has that same thing
then they can bring it up but it's not
necessarily right and wrong it's not
just like it's a feeling inside of me if
I just counted the feeling instead the
thing when I wasn't supposed to there's
learning there same with if I stayed
silent when I was supposed to feet speak
up there's learning there could because
when I'm supposed to speak up and I do
and I see what happens that's where more
and more learning happens rapidly who's
like the good stuff happens which is
learning so all this stuff is good stuff
all right I need to go and see my kid
get her breakfast now that she's awake
for
few minutes before the roundtable it
runs together Czech tech channel if you
want to come and participate in that
you'll have to be in the Facebook group
but if you want to come watch it yeah
there is a link in the description
watching for a couple weeks and then you
can come and join the Facebook group and
participate in them in the roundtables
in the board mediums and in creating a
world that works for everyone thank you
for hanging out and tomorrow will be my
last day I don't quite yet know what I'm
talking about but it's Sunday storytime
and hopefully other people come enjoying
and then like I said I'm taking next
week off something I did say that during
this conversation but I've set out in
previous videos taking next week off
beside solution raising and my other day
on the textile happening
that's not thinking a week off but I'm
no longer doing the possibility the
pandemic and then the following week I
will also be doing a process raising
hopefully week one or two other people
weekly and then as I feel the actual
need to add one that is the dance and
one that is the technology Commons
conversation I will add those as well
but I don't need to